The SCOAN Sunday Service
Good Morning!
I say, "Good Morning".
Viewers all over the world, I salute your faith.
Good Morning to you!
You may be seated.
Hallelujah!
Let me quickly take you up on a message titled
GOD’S LOVE NEVER FAILS
Let's take our reading.
I will take you to different Books in the New Testament.
We will take the first reading from the Book of Romans 8 and we start our reading from verse 35 to the end.
That will be our first reading.
After that, we will go to the Book of Joshua 1:9 - it is also very key for this message.
After leaving that Book, we will also find our root in the Book of Matthew 6 from verse 25.
Our root concerning the message, "GOD'S LOVE NEVER FAILS".
That is Matthew 6:25.
When we leave there, we have other Books too that will help us - the Book of Numbers 20:8.
Let's now go to the Book of 1 Corinthians 1:8 - it will be a wonderful reading for us.
And 2 Corinthians too, chapter 12: 7-10 - it will be also very useful for us.
Take your Bible when you get home - you have enough time for this.
After listening to the message, you will be able to find more details about these Books given to you:
the Book of Joshua 1:9,
the Book of Romans 8:35 - 38 - it will be very useful showing that God's love never fails,
and the Book of Matthew - the issue of worry; it is detailed in the Book of Matthew 6:25 - very important.
And 1 Corinthians 1:18,
2 Corinthians 12:7 - 10 about Apostle Paul, the thorn; that will be very useful.
Let's go to the Book of Romans first.
Life through the Spirit - Romans 8.
“Therefore, there is now no condemnation for those who are in Christ Jesus,
because through Christ Jesus the law of the Spirit who gives life
has set you free from the law of sin and death.”
Let's go to our proof reading - verse 35.
“Who shall separate us from the love of Christ?
Shall trouble or hardship or persecution or famine or nakedness or danger or sword?
As it is written: ‘For your sake we face death all day long;
we are considered as sheep to be slaughtered.’"
Verse 37.
“No, in all these things we are more than conquerors through Him who loved us."
“For I am convinced that neither death nor life, neither angels nor demons,
neither the present nor the future, nor any powers…”
Take your time and read it from verse 35 to the end.
Yes.
God's love never fails.
That Book of Romans, chapter 8 verse 35 to the end.
What can separate us from the love of Christ?
Can worry?
Because this is the problem today.
When you ask your brother, he will tell you, "I'm worried. I will not be able to see T.B. Joshua before I leave today.
I'm worried; I will not be able to be prayed for.
I'm worried if I'm going to see this man one on one - I have problem" - worry.
Can worry ... - worry about what?
Families.
Can worry ... worry about present?
Can worry ... worry about the future?
What can separate you?
Can worry, worry about your work responsibilities... "How will I go about it?"
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Can worry ... worry about your weight?
Many people complain about their weight, "I'm too fat..." - worry about weight.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Worry, worry, worry...
The list of worries is endless.
"I'm dark in complexion; I want to bleach my colour.
I have an oblong face; I need a round face.
My nose is too small; I want to operate it.
I want to add more to my 'bum bum'."
Worry, worry, worry...
"There are so many gaps in my teeth; I need to operate it.
Look at what the man of God wears today; I need this suit."
After the break you go to the car-park, you look around at different kinds of cars,
"My God, I need this jeep."
Worry, worry, worry...
Worry interferes with God’s Spirit in our life.
Worry interferes with God’s Spirit and you need God’s Spirit.
"I want to add to my hair, I need some wig."
Worry, worry, worry...
Each time you look in the mirror, you have something to worry about,
because of the way you look and the way others look.
Worry, worry...
The list of worries is endless.
Despite all these worries, God’s love for us remains unfailing.
The reality is this: We all experience worry, including me.
Ask me what is my worry.
You – how you will get Heaven because of inconsistency.
Because Jesus will come like a thief in the night.
No one knows when and how.
Where will you be?
If I know you today, I may not know you tomorrow.
If you are with me today, you may not be with me tomorrow.
Where will you be?
Will you be ready when the Lord shall come
I will be ready
When the Lord shall come
Worries interfere with God’s Spirit in our life.
Many are here, but they are not here because of worry.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We all experience worry.
Worry about present, worry about our future, worry about failure.
Even the great heroes of our faith experienced their own share of worry about failure.
That is why I give you those Books to read.
Don't forget to add Genesis 20:1-end to the Books I gave you to read.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Even the great heroes of our faith experienced their own share of failure.
Abraham, Moses, Elijah, John, Peter, Paul -
they all knew what it was like to make serious mistakes
but God used even their mistakes to bring them to the place where He wanted them to be.
Because God never created failure.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Tell your neighbour, “I want to be the person You created, oh Lord.”
He never created failure; there is no failure in Him.
Say, “I want to be the person You created”.
Today, everybody desires breakthrough.
Today, everybody desires success,
whereas disappointment sometimes serves to keep us for success.
Failure sometimes serves to keep us from breakthrough.
Setback sometimes serves to keep us for the future we desire.
God used their failure to bring them to the place where He wanted them to be, the place of honour.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
In that reading given to you, you will find that
Abraham failed God when he fled to Egypt during the drought.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Moses lost his temper and turned to violence more than once.
He lost his temper.
Are you talking of David?
He committed murder and adultery.
Peter denied Jesus Christ
and yet the Lord used all the people who failed Him.
No matter how many times you fail, His love never does.
There are many successful people out there in our society all over the world
that have once had the same experience you are going through -
failure, setback, sickness, disease but today, God has changed their story.
Ask successful people out there; they will tell you how much disappointment they have endured,
how much sickness they have endured, how much failure they have endured,
how much stagnation they have endured
to come to their breakthrough, to the place of honour, the future they deserve.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Reason well as a Christian – you will see why you are going through the challenges you have.
Do what?
With deep reflection, you will see why you are going through the challenges.
With deep reflection, you will see why you are going through the situation.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It takes faith to realise that our situation is a mere stopping interval,
a short break between two events.
It takes faith, not experience we use today -
because you have gone all over the world, you are well educated.
No, not experience – faith.
It takes faith to realise that our situation is a mere stopping interval – a transit point to connect.
Not your destination – it is a preparation to success.
Not your destination – it is a bridge to success.
What is your situation?
Ask your neighbour.
[What is your situation?]
I cannot heart you.
I cannot hear you.
[What is your situation?]
I cannot heart you.
What are you going through?
Is it inability to get a job in spite of your qualifications?
Is it inability to get a job?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
What are you going through, what are the challenges?
The great heroes of our faith had their own share of challenges
and God used their challenges to bring them to the place where He wanted them to be.
With deep reflection, you will see reason why you are going through your challenges.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Challenge is not a crisis; it’s a friend.
It’s a bridge; it’s a preparation.
It’s a stopping interval; it’s not a crisis.
Lord, in spite of our weaknesses, in spite of our failure, help us to learn from them.
It is a school of lessons.
Your challenge is a school of lessons but you don’t look at it that way.
You look at it as a crisis.
Where will you learn?
That is the best college, which is better than the one you go to out there.
Challenges are the best college to learn how to handle your future.
You have to learn once and for all from your challenges
and get connected to the future you deserve.
It’s a bridge; get connected.
Learn and get connected.
If not, it will be throwback.
Many challenges you are facing today, and you are not supposed to.
You have someone helping you to push your challenges somewhere,
not in a normal way, but it is there to push it somewhere.
You know this thing is not right for you.
You get it at all cost because you have somebody to help you - but it will be throwback.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It will become a carry-over to our life.
Finally, this is a word of exhortation:
What we see as a failure is not failure at all from eternity’s perspective – from God’s angle.
What we see as a failure is not failure at all.
What we see as a failure is not failure at all from eternity’s perspective.
Jesus’ death on the Cross – His disciples at first thought it was failure
but what looked like a failure brought new life to all mankind.
Look at the case of Peter at the seaside, "I will make you a fisher of men, if you follow Me".
From disappointment to what?
Don't forget about Hannah; at what age...?
Worry about money, worry about relationships, worry about work responsibilities,
worry about someone who disappointed you -
all those things are a trap of the enemy to interfere with God’s Spirit in your life.
Once you are worried, nothing can work here;
nothing, even the Spirit of God cannot - nothing, you are for satan when you are worried.
At the moment you start worrying, you are a servant of satan.
If I am worried, I will not come here.
I would not be able to come here
and if I force myself to come here, I would not be able to represent God here today.
Worry can cause hypertension, heart attack, blood pressure; just name those things worry can cause,
my dear brother.
It interferes with God's Spirit in our life.
Worry, worry, worry...
You don’t have to worry
And don’t you be afraid
Joy comes in the morning
Troubles they won’t last always
Remember there’s a Friend named Jesus
Who will wipe your tears away
And if your heart is broken
Just lift your hands and say
I know that I can make it
I know that I can stand
No matter what may come my way
My life is in Your hands
With Jesus I can take it
With Him I know I can stand
No matter what may come my way
My life is in Your hands
You don’t have to worry
And don’t you be afraid
Joy comes in the morning
Troubles they won’t last always
Remember there’s a Friend named Jesus
Who will wipe your tears away
And if your heart is broken
Just lift your hands and say
I know that I can make it
I know that I can stand
No matter what may come my way
My life is in Your hands
With Jesus I can take it
With Him I know I can stand
No matter what may come my way
My life is in Your hands
Tell your neighbour,
What you see as a failure may not be at all – stop worrying.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Something that stands as a preparation, a bridge – can we call it a crisis?
Can we call preparation a crisis?
Can we call a bridge a crisis?
Can we call a stopping interval a crisis?
Can we call a transit point a crisis?
Can we call getting connected a crisis?
That are the challenges.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Whatever challenges you are going through, whether sickness,
all you need – you need to be a Christian.
Once you are a Christian, your challenges are not like others.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Listen!
Once you are a Christian, your sickness is not like others.
Your sickness is to preserve you, to keep you for a new level.
It may be to stop you awhile.
When you are stopped awhile, it is time to prepare you for the challenges ahead.
That is it.
Once you have whatever sickness,
or challenge that could be stagnation, joblessness, barrenness, loneliness...
That you are a Christian does not mean you cannot get sick
but your sickness is not like others.
Tell your neighbour,
That you are a Christian does not mean you cannot get sick
but your sickness is not like others.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Can you face your neighbour and tell:
That I am a Christian does not mean I cannot face challenges,
does not mean I cannot face situations but my challenges, my situations are not like others.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Others, their situation is to destroy them, to kill them, to wreck them, to sink them
but your own situation – you just need to be one with Jesus.
If anyone tells you that as a Christian, you cannot get sick, that is a wrong doctrine.
Where do you put Apostle Paul?
“When I am weak, then I am strong.”
When you are sick, then you are in good health.
When you are sick, then you are healed.
When you are stuck, then you are moving.
When you have failed, then you have success.
That is it.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Lesson, lesson, lesson; you need to grow.
Everyone; as I am here now, I need to grow more.
And to grow...
The best lesson, the best examination for growing is challenges.
You learn better in challenges.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
What we see as failure may not be from eternity’s perspective.
That your sickness, that your failure, that your setback, delayed pregnancy,
whatever you call it that you are facing does not mean you are not a Christian.
Don’t allow your situation to rule you, to dictate to you whether you are a Christian or not.
“Because I am poor, I am not a Christian.”
A man can be poor and yet be a friend of Jesus.
Are you with me?
A man can be sick in body and yet be a candidate of Heaven.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You may be seated.
God’s love never fails.
The trap satan sets out there now for Christians is worry.
When the people of the world realise that you are happy, they dial your number,
"What can I tell this person? He is too happy."
"Hello. I had a very bad dream about you. Once I dreamt about this person and it happened,
and I dreamt about this person and it happened..."
By the time he has given you 5 good examples,
you will start urinating.
- "I dreamt about this, that. Go and ask..."
- "How can I see you?"
- "See me? OK, come."
Because he knows you are happy, he wants to make you sad, worried.
By then, he might have gathered some information about you.
Just to make you worried.
Worry interferes with God’s Spirit in your life.
Tell your neighbour,
Worry interferes with God’s Spirit in our life.
Once you are worried...
If I'm worried now, and I stretch my hand to say, "Be healed!", I'm talking to myself.
No healing; nothing.
If I just go there and say, "Be healed!", I'm hearing myself and you are hearing me, but God...
I would be hearing myself and you around me would be hearing me, but God...
Because I'm what?
I'm worried.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Those of you that wake up in the morning; you want to make your husband worried, your wife worried,
somebody worried; on the phone, you are good in giving negative news.
Worry, worry, worry...
I want to leave you here.
I know you have a lot of lessons to learn today.
How will you deal with worry?
Ask your neighbour, "How will you deal with worry?"
Little, little...
Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
TT ROBERT BEGIER 28/09/2018
RV: Mel Flowers 29/09/2018